const essentialsChapter3QuizData = [
  {
    id: "3_1",
    question: "In certain situations, jobs are so critical that they can be done in haste and with a disregard to you personal safety. (Page 19)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_2",
    question: "How should the ladder be secured during transportation? (Page 20)",
    options: ["Secured at only one rack support point", "Secured at each rack support point with maximum overhang", "It doesn't matter. Just throw it on the vehicle.", "Secured at each rack support point with minimum overhang"],
    answer: "Secured at each rack support point with minimum overhang"
  },
  {
    id: "3_3",
    question: "Before moving the vehicle, you should _________. (Page 20)",
    options: ["Call the office", "Walk around the vehicle to be sure everything is in order and secure", "Yell BYE at the homeowner", "Eat your lunch"],
    answer: "Walk around the vehicle to be sure everything is in order and secure"
  },
  {
    id: "3_4",
    question: "Before you set up your ladder, you should _________. (Page 21)",
    options: ["Carry the ladder to the location vertically", "Walk around the house to be sure that you have chosen the best location", "Always use the porch since it is usually clear", "Ignore power lines"],
    answer: "Walk around the house to be sure that you have chosen the best location"
  },
  {
    id: "3_5",
    question: "You should always carry the ladder _________. (Page 21)",
    options: ["By dragging it on the ground", "Vertically", "Horizontally", "Above your head"],
    answer: "Horizontally"
  },
  {
    id: "3_6",
    question: "As long as you are not touching the power line with your ladder, you are fine. (Page 21)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_7",
    question: "What distance can electricity jump? (Page 21)",
    options: ["Several Feet", "Under 1 foot", "It can't, it must be contacted", "Over 30 yards"],
    answer: "Several Feet"
  },
  {
    id: "3_8",
    question: "It is alright to have different surfaces under your ladder's legs. For example: It is ok for one leg to be on the grass, while the other is on the sidewalk. (Page 21)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_9",
    question: "At a minimum how many rungs above the roof should your ladder be? (Page 21)",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    answer: "3"
  },
  {
    id: "3_10",
    question: "At a minimum how many inches above the roof should your ladder be? (Page 21)",
    options: ["12", "24", "36", "48"],
    answer: "36"
  },
  {
    id: "3_11",
    question: "When placing a ladder, it should be placed at a _________ angle. (Page 21)",
    options: ["3:1", "4:1", "5:1", "2:1"],
    answer: "4:1"
  },
  {
    id: "3_12",
    question: "If a ladder is set up to be 36 ft tall, how far away from the house should the base of the ladder be? (Page 21)",
    options: ["4 feet", "6 feet", "9 feet", "12 feet"],
    answer: "9 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "3_13",
    question: "What is a decent way to gauge if you have the ladder at the correct angle? (Page 21)",
    options: ["Look at it from the side and form an 'L' with your fingers", "Begin climbing and go by feel", "Stand at the base of the ladder and make sure your hands can reach it if holding them straight out", "Ask someone if it looks good"],
    answer: "Stand at the base of the ladder and make sure your hands can reach it if holding them straight out"
  },
  {
    id: "3_14",
    question: "Stepladders should be no more than _________ below the height you want to work at. (Page 21)",
    options: ["1 foot", "2 feet", "3 feet", "4 feet"],
    answer: "4 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "3_15",
    question: "You should never work of the top 2 rungs or the top of the ladder. (Page 21)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_16",
    question: "A general rule of thumb suggests that the ladder is _________ to _________ longer than necessary to reach the highest support point. (Page 21)",
    options: ["3 to 5 feet", "4 to 7 feet", "7 to 10 feet", "10 to 15 feet"],
    answer: "7 to 10 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "3_17",
    question: "Twisting on a ladder does not put you in danger of falling. (Page 22)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_18",
    question: "You should always try to secure your ladder at the point of contact at the top of the ladder, especially when working in windy conditions. (Page 22)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_19",
    question: "You should always use EXTREME CAUTION when using aluminum ladders near power lines because _________. (Page 22)",
    options: ["It can mean instant death if contacted with a power line", "Aluminum ladders conduct electricity", "Electric can jump from the power line", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these"
  },
  {
    id: "3_20",
    question: "Ladders should be kept at a minimum of _________ from any power line. (Page 22)",
    options: ["5 feet", "10 feet", "15 feet", "20 feet"],
    answer: "10 feet"
  },
  {
    id: "3_21",
    question: "Decks usually provide adequate traction for ladders. (Page 22)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_22",
    question: "When moving up or down a ladder, you should always face the ladder. (Page 23)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_23",
    question: "_________ must be provided on stepladders to hold the front and back sections in an open position when ladders are being used. (Page 23)",
    options: ["A person manually holding the ladder", "Metal spreaders or locking devices", "Ratchet Straps", "2x4s"],
    answer: "Metal spreaders or locking devices"
  },
  {
    id: "3_24",
    question: "Ladders with structural defects, such as broken or missing rungs, cleats, or steps, broken or split rails; corroded components; or other faulty or defective components, do not have to immediately be marked as defective. (Page 23)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_25",
    question: "Not every roofing material is slick when wet or damp. (Page 24)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_26",
    question: "These roofing materials are prone to moss and other growths. In addition, stepping on this moss can result in a slip. (Page 24)",
    options: ["Wood Shakes Only", "Asphalt Shingles Only", "Metal Roofs", "Both Wood Shakes and Asphalt Shingles"],
    answer: "Both Wood Shakes and Asphalt Shingles"
  },
  {
    id: "3_27",
    question: "What makes Wood Shakes, Slate, and Tile Roofs a pain? (Page 24)",
    options: ["They are usually found on cheaper houses", "They are easily breakable", "They are found on extremely tall houses", "You need a permit to be able to even step on them"],
    answer: "They are easily breakable"
  },
  {
    id: "3_28",
    question: "You should not wear slick soled shoes because they do not provide good traction on roofs. (Page 24)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_29",
    question: "What point of the roof is stronger and easier to climb? (Page 24)",
    options: ["The side that usually faces the wind", "On the porch overhang", "On the very edge", "At the ridge and valleys"],
    answer: "At the ridge and valleys"
  },
  {
    id: "3_30",
    question: "Warped and sunken areas usually indicate a strong point on the roof? (Page 24)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_31",
    question: "A _________ is used to navigate steep roof and also stay off fragile or slippery roofs. This is slid up the roof until the hook passes over the peak, and then it is flipped over. (Page 25)",
    options: ["Scaffolding", "Stepladder", "Roof Ladder and Ridge Hook", "Extension Ladder"],
    answer: "Roof Ladder and Ridge Hook"
  },
  {
    id: "3_32",
    question: "It is alright to lean a ladder against a chimney if there are visible signs of deterioration, because after all, it is solid masonry. (Page 25)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_33",
    question: "You should always use extreme caution leaning a ladder against a wooden chimney chase because it may not be structurally sound or properly secured. (Page 25)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_34",
    question: "According to the Chimney And Venting Essentials book, when can you sit or stand on top of a chimney? (Page 25)",
    options: ["Never", "When stretching a liner", "When dropping a liner", "When it is not wet, damp or slippery"],
    answer: "Never"
  },
  {
    id: "3_35",
    question: "According to the Chimney And Venting Essentials book, when can you stand on a chase cover while performing work on a factory-built chimney? (Page 25)",
    options: ["Never", "When replacing the chase cover", "When inspecting or sweeping the chimney", "When it is not wet, damp or slippery"],
    answer: "Never"
  },
  {
    id: "3_36",
    question: "According to the Chimney And Venting Essentials book, when can you sit or stand on top of a chimney? (Page 25)",
    options: ["Never", "When stretching a liner", "When dropping a liner", "When it is not wet, damp or slippery"],
    answer: "Never"
  },
  {
    id: "3_37",
    question: "_________ and _________ are the 2 common methods of cleaning chimneys from the roof. (Page 26)",
    options: ["Rotary Sweeping and Traditional Chimney Rods", "Chemical Coating and PCR", "Tuckpointing And Waterproofing", "Ridge Hooking and Brushing"],
    answer: "Rotary Sweeping and Traditional Chimney Rods"
  },
  {
    id: "3_38",
    question: "Because the Rods can become detached and you can lose your balance due to a sudden lack of tension, you should never push or pull rods with sufficient force when sweeping from the top. (Page 26)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_39",
    question: "Why should you not throw stuff off the roof? (Page 26)",
    options: ["It could cause damage to the homeowner's property", "It could damage the tools, if a tool was the object thrown", "It could cause injury or fatality to someone below", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these"
  },
  {
    id: "3_40",
    question: "One of the most common injuries suffered by chimney technicians is to the _________. (Page 26)",
    options: ["Back", "Shoulders", "Head", "Fingers"],
    answer: "Back"
  },
  {
    id: "3_41",
    question: "When picking something up, squat by bending your _________. (Page 27)",
    options: ["Knees", "Waist", "Back", "Obliques"],
    answer: "Knees"
  },
  {
    id: "3_42",
    question: "When lifting, you should _________. (Page 27)",
    options: ["Lift straight up, do not bend forward", "Bend forward and lift straight up", "Never ask for help because you will be made fun of", "Twist towards your destination as you stand so that you can move the object quicker"],
    answer: "Lift straight up, do not bend forward"
  },
  {
    id: "3_43",
    question: "How should you set your load down? (Page 27)",
    options: ["Drop it, but make sure you don't hit your toes", "Slowly bend over at your waist and gently sit the load on the floor", "Squat, allowing the muscles of your legs and buttocks to do the work", "Grunt like a tennis player"],
    answer: "Squat, allowing the muscles of your legs and buttocks to do the work"
  },
  {
    id: "3_44",
    question: "_________ is something employers should have available for all employees. It is for all products that technicians use in the business. This is divided into sections that include identification, physical data, reactivity, health hazard data, environmental impact, exposure control methods, work practices, emergency procedures, and first aid/medical emergency procedures. (Page 27)",
    options: ["Equipment Identification Sheet", "Safety Data Sheets", "Product Instructions", "Equipment Checklists"],
    answer: "Safety Data Sheets"
  },
  {
    id: "3_45",
    question: "Where do copies of the SDS (Safety Data Sheets) need to be? (Page 27)",
    options: ["At your house so you can study and memorize them", "Wherever an employee meets a potentially hazardous material", "Wherever the AHJ determines", "In the homeowners personal records"],
    answer: "Wherever an employee meets a potentially hazardous material"
  },
  {
    id: "3_46",
    question: "When it comes to ANSI, ALL hardhats must comply with _________? (Page 28)",
    options: ["ANSI Z89.1", "ANSI Z21.8", "ANSI A89.1", "ANSI A21.8"],
    answer: "ANSI Z89.1"
  },
  {
    id: "3_47",
    question: "This class of helmet is intended to reduce the force of impact resulting in a blow only to the top of the head. (Page 28)",
    options: ["Type 1", "Type 2", "Class E (Formerly Class B)", "Class G (Formerly Class A)", "Class C"],
    answer: "Type 1"
  },
  {
    id: "3_48",
    question: "This class of helmet is intended to reduce the force of impact resulting in a blow to the top of the head and the side of the head. (Page 28)",
    options: ["Type 1", "Type 2", "Class E (Formerly Class B)", "Class G (Formerly Class A)", "Class C"],
    answer: "Type 2"
  },
  {
    id: "3_49",
    question: "This class of helmet is for use where electrical hazards are present and intended to protect against falling objects and reduce the danger of exposure to high voltage electrical shocks and burns. Offers the highest protection with high-voltage shock and burn protection up to 20,000 volts. (Page 28)",
    options: ["Type 1", "Type 2", "Class E (Formerly Class B)", "Class G (Formerly Class A)", "Class C"],
    answer: "Class E (Formerly Class B)"
  },
  {
    id: "3_50",
    question: "This class of helmet is for general use intended to protect against falling objects and reduce the danger of exposure to low voltage electrical conductors. They provide impact and penetration resistance and protection from up to 2,200 volts. (Page 28)",
    options: ["Type 1", "Type 2", "Class E (Formerly Class B)", "Class G (Formerly Class A)", "Class C"],
    answer: "Class G (Formerly Class A)"
  },
  {
    id: "3_51",
    question: "This class of helmet is not tested for electrical resistance . They are designed for lightweight comfort and impact protection and are not intended to provide protection from electrical conductors. (Page 28)",
    options: ["Type 1", "Type 2", "Class E (Formerly Class B)", "Class G (Formerly Class A)", "Class C"],
    answer: "Class C"
  },
  {
    id: "3_52",
    question: "Liners or sweatbands can be added to hard hats / helmets to aid in warmth or cooling. (Page 28)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_53",
    question: "When it comes to eye protection, street wear frames with safety lenses are in compliance. (Page 29)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_54",
    question: "What is the cure for noise induced hearing loss? (Page 30)",
    options: ["There is none", "Surgery", "Medication", "Wearing noise canceling ear protection for a month so that your ears can heal"],
    answer: "There is none"
  },
  {
    id: "3_55",
    question: "A chimney technician should wear a respirator to filter _________? (Page 30)",
    options: ["Dust and Organic Vapors", "Only Dust", "Only Organic Vapors", "Fly Ash"],
    answer: "Dust and Organic Vapors"
  },
  {
    id: "3_56",
    question: "Negative Pressure Respirators rely on _________? (Page 30)",
    options: ["A motor that pulls fresh air into the mask", "Physics related to the user's elevation level", "The user's own breathing power", "Clean external air"],
    answer: "The user's own breathing power"
  },
  {
    id: "3_57",
    question: "Powered Air Protection Respirators (PAPR) rely on _________? (Page 30)",
    options: ["A motor that pulls air through the filter and blows fresh air into the mask", "Physics related to the user's elevation level", "The user's own breathing power", "Clean external air"],
    answer: "A motor that pulls air through the filter and blows fresh air into the mask"
  },
  {
    id: "3_58",
    question: "When it comes to gloves, they must provide required protection AND the manual dexterity needed to perform the required task(s)? (Page 31)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_59",
    question: "When you are using rotary cleaning systems, what should you do when it comes to the spinning rods? (Page 31)",
    options: ["Make sure you use a piece of garden hose or PVC Pipe around it so that your hand and gloves don't get entangled and cause injury", "Grip it loosely while using gloves so that your gloves don't get entangled and cause injury", "If you grab them, make sure to take your gloves off first so that they don't get entangled and cause injury", "Have one person control the drill, while the other grabs and guides the rods"],
    answer: "Make sure you use a piece of garden hose or PVC Pipe around it so that your hand and gloves don't get entangled and cause injury"
  },
  {
    id: "3_60",
    question: "When it comes to footwear, you should avoid slick or smooth soles such as leather. (Page 31)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_61",
    question: "You should always be careful around fuse boxes and circuit breaker panels. You should NEVER touch a fuse box or circuit breaker panel if there is water on the floor. (Page 31)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_62",
    question: "OSHA requires on the job fatalities to be reported within _________. (Page 32)",
    options: ["30 minutes if possible", "4 hours", "8 hours", "24 hours"],
    answer: "8 hours"
  },
  {
    id: "3_63",
    question: "OSHA requires on the job accidents resulting in the loss of an eye, amputation or in-patient hospitalization to be reported within _________. (Page 32)",
    options: ["48 hours", "36 hours", "8 hours", "24 hours"],
    answer: "24 hours"
  },
  {
    id: "3_64",
    question: "Soot and creosote are derivatives of _________. (Page 32)",
    options: ["Chimney Sweeping", "The combustion process", "Condensation in the flue", "Chemical Flue Cleaning"],
    answer: "The combustion process"
  },
  {
    id: "3_65",
    question: "Aromatic hydrocarbons related to derivatives of the combustion process are _________. (Page 32)",
    options: ["Proven Carcinogens (cancer-causing)", "Good smelling odors", "Healthy", "Only able to enter the body through the lungs"],
    answer: "Proven Carcinogens (cancer-causing)"
  },
  {
    id: "3_66",
    question: "Swallowed soot can enter the intestinal tract, therefore medical professionals have advised if you cough it up, you should _________. (Page 32)",
    options: ["Spit it out", "Swallow it again", "It can't enter the intestinal tract", "Hold it in your mouth for at least 10 seconds so it can be diluted by your saliva"],
    answer: "Spit it out"
  },
  {
    id: "3_67",
    question: "Because of soot, when it comes to clothing it is best to wear _________. (Page 32)",
    options: ["Long pants and socks", "Shorts in the summer so you can quickly wipe the soot off", "Whatever makes you comfortable", "Bulky gloves, even if they hinder your dexterity"],
    answer: "Long pants and socks"
  },
  {
    id: "3_68",
    question: "Raccoons can carry both _________ and _________. (Page 33)",
    options: ["Ringworm and Covid", "Roundworm and Rabies", "Rabies and Tapeworm", "Rabies and Histoplasmosis"],
    answer: "Roundworm and Rabies"
  },
  {
    id: "3_69",
    question: "Squirrels need to be removed from chimneys. Their nest can stay. (Page 33)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_70",
    question: "After ensuring all animals have been removed, a _________ should be installed to prevent recurring animal invasions. (Page 33)",
    options: ["Screened Chimney Cap", "Stainless Steel Liner", "Crown", "Trap"],
    answer: "Screened Chimney Cap"
  },
  {
    id: "3_71",
    question: "_________ tend to nest in chimneys. (Page 34)",
    options: ["Owls", "Chimney Swifts", "Robins", "Hawks"],
    answer: "Chimney Swifts"
  },
  {
    id: "3_72",
    question: "The _________ provides protection to Chimney Swifts and their nests. (Page 34)",
    options: ["NFPA 211", "Migratory Bird Treaty Act", "US Constitution", "IRC"],
    answer: "Migratory Bird Treaty Act"
  },
  {
    id: "3_73",
    question: "If you encounter an active Chimney Swift nest, you are allowed to remove it. (Page 34)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_74",
    question: "Along with Chimney Swifts, many common bats and a few squirrels are also protected. (Page 34)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_75",
    question: "In some parts of the country, small animals, including raccoons, foxes, opossums, skunks, rabbits, squirrels, rats, mice, and bats are currently at high risk of _________. (Page 35)",
    options: ["Rabies", "Roundworm", "Covid", "Histoplasmosis"],
    answer: "Rabies"
  },
  {
    id: "3_76",
    question: "Bat feces and urine can sometimes contain _________. (Page 35)",
    options: ["Rabies", "Roundworm", "Covid", "Histoplasmosis"],
    answer: "Rabies"
  },
  {
    id: "3_77",
    question: "_________ are the most likely source if you do contract rabies. (Page 35)",
    options: ["Raccoons", "Skunks", "Bats", "Squirrels"],
    answer: "Bats"
  },
  {
    id: "3_78",
    question: "You will always know if you've been bitten by a bat. (Page 35)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "3_79",
    question: "If you suspect rabies exposure, it is mandatory to seek medical attention _________. (Page 35)",
    options: ["Immediately", "Within 8 hours", "Within 24 hours", "At the first sign of symptoms"],
    answer: "Immediately"
  },
  {
    id: "3_80",
    question: "Once rabies symptoms appear, it is nearly _________ fatal. (Page 35)",
    options: ["100%", "75%", "50%", "90%"],
    answer: "100%"
  },
  {
    id: "3_81",
    question: "In addition to rabies, raccoons can carry _________. (Page 35)",
    options: ["Ringworm", "Roundworm", "Tapeworm", "Histoplasmosis"],
    answer: "Roundworm"
  },
  {
    id: "3_82",
    question: "Fecal matter of raccoons infected with roundworm contains roundworm eggs or larvae. (Page 35)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "3_83",
    question: "After raccoons are removed, you should disinfect the smoke shelf with _________ to kill any roundworm eggs that remain in the chimney. (Page 36)",
    options: ["Bleach", "Soap and Water", "Vinegar", "Off"],
    answer: "Bleach"
  },
  {
    id: "3_84",
    question: "Dispose of raccoon excrement by _________. (Page 36)",
    options: ["Burning or burying it in a landfill", "Throwing it away", "Calling ODNR", "Spraying it with water until is disappears"],
    answer: "Burning or burying it in a landfill"
  },
  {
    id: "3_85",
    question: "_________ is a fungal infection most commonly of the respiratory system, though symptoms can vary widely. (Page 36)",
    options: ["Covid", "Histoplasmosis", "Pneumonia", "General Allergies"],
    answer: "Histoplasmosis"
  },
  {
    id: "3_86",
    question: "These two things contain a much higher concentration of Histoplasmosis. (Page 36)",
    options: ["Raccoon Feces and Flue Openings", "Bird Droppings and Bat Guano", "Chimney Swift Nests and Clogged Chimney Caps", "Creosote and Soot"],
    answer: "Bird Droppings and Bat Guano"
  },
  {
    id: "3_87",
    question: "Chimney Technicians should always carry a can of special wasp and hornet spray that sprays at least _________ feet. (Page 37)",
    options: ["25", "20", "15", "10"],
    answer: "25"
  },
  {
    id: "3_88",
    question: "What is one reason why you should wear a respirator while sweeping oil and coal flues. (Page 37)",
    options: ["The soot and fumes combine with moisture to produce Sulfuric Acid, which could render you breathless", "You can instantly die", "Arsenic compounds can cause de-pigmentation of the skin", "They always contain histoplasmosis"],
    answer: "The soot and fumes combine with moisture to produce Sulfuric Acid, which could render you breathless"
  },
];

if (!window.quizRegistry) window.quizRegistry = {};
window.quizRegistry['Chapter 3: Health and Safety at the Job Site'] = essentialsChapter3QuizData;
